Diego de Almeida Cunha

Full Stack Developer React/React Native + Node Phone: +55 (41) 99794-3868

E-mail: diegoalmda@gmail.com
Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/diegoalmda/

About Me

I am a technologist in Telematics, with more than 3 years of experience working as a web developer. I have knowledge in web and mobile applications development focusing on JavaScript language and React.is, React Native and Node.js libraries.

I know advanced SEO techniques for website optimization and accessibility, allowing the user experience to become more inclusive. I also master web responsiveness resources, favoring the use of applications on devices with different screen sizes while maintaining a great user experience.

I have advanced knowledge in Next.js, Typescript, REST APIs or GraphQL and with test-oriented development. I can create an application from the design project in tools such as Figma, using UX/UI techniques, to deployment with continuous integration and deliveries, always focusing on good practices.

I have a flexible profile, which allows me to work in different areas and activities at the same time in an organized way, knowing how to distinguish between more urgent tasks and non-urgent tasks. Working this way, I can stay focused when I'm under a lot of demand, which allows me to deliver projects on time.

Education

IFPB

Telematics Technology • 2008 - 2013

Work Experience

Freelance • Curitiba/PR • 03/2020 - present

Position: Full Stack Web Developer

- Creation and maintenance of websites.
- Gathering requirements of applications, and systems implementation.
- Development and maintenance of applications with JavaScript, React and Node.js, Relational and non-relational databases.

Main achievements:

 Creation of websites with customer feedback regarding success with the implementation of SEO techniques that made the businesses gain more visibility and reach new relevant customers.

ITS Importação, Tecnologia e Serviços • São José dos Pinhais/PR • 08/2021 – 02/2022 Large company in the graphic material production sector

Position: Front-end Developer

- Development and maintenance of systems using React.js, HTML, CSS, jQuery.
- Modify programs, changing processing, coding and other elements.
- Fix bugs and address system changes and support new features.

Main achievements:

 I left a position where I was focused on maintenance and development of small features to become responsible for creating the front-end of a new e-commerce in partnership with a teammate responsible for the back-end of the application. I took as a basis a layout provided by

- the design team and used, as main technologies: React, Styled-components, Redux and REST API.
- I developed an app with React Native to read the bar code of orders and collect the signature of
 the person who received the order with integration of the company's logistics system, to update
 the status of orders. This application resulted in an automation of order write-offs, making it no
 longer necessary to carry out the manual procedure.

Empresa Brasileira de Correios e Telégrafos S.A. • 03/2013 – 02/2021

Large company in the logistics sector

Position: Commercial Attendant

- Customer Service.
- Selling products and providing postage services.
- Performing over-the-counter banking services.

Main achievements:

Negotiation of new contracts between Correios and new corporate clients.

Technical Soluções em Informática LTDA • 02/2012 – 03/2013

Position: Technical support and installer of telecommunication equipment

- In-home and telephone technical support.
- Installation and configuration of telecommunication equipment.
- Monitoring of network stations.
- Technical team management.

Main achievements:

• I started to control the technical team responsible for new installations and maintenance.

Online Courses

React.js, Node.js, React Native - Practical content, projects and performance challenges - 300h - 2022 Complete course of Node.js - 50h - 2021 Complete course of Javascript from beginner to master - 70h - 2020

Languages

English - Advanced Portuguese - Native

Portfolio

https://www.diegoalmeida.tech/